Zento De Houwer

Software Developer

Zento De Houwer

Schutsboomstraat 7 2340 Beerse Belgium

+32478508952 zentodehouwer@gmail.com BE1009.494.935

About me

My name is Zento De Houwer. I'm Belgian and I've lived and worked in Ireland for 3 years. I'm **fluent in English** and my native tongue **Dutch** and have really **basic French**. In my free time I like to listen and play music. I play the drums, play the guitar and sing a bit. I love nature, hiking, camping, travelling and exploring new things to learn. Tech and non tech.

Experience

Exads / Senior Angular developer

APR 2022 - PRESENT, DUBLIN - IRELAND (REMOTE FROM SLIGO)

I started at the company as an **Angular** front end developer. After a year I started contributing to refactors, performance improvements and the architecture. After a year and a half I became full stack where I started developing in **PHP**. Besides that I also became a system lead for the open source project, Fluid Player. Written in pure **JavaScript**.

Memfies / Full stack developer

FEB 2019 - JAN 2022, SLIGO - IRELAND

At Memfies, I built their service from the ground up as the sole full-time developer. This Included developing a web app in **Angular**, a mobile app in **Ionic** and **Angular** for Android and iOS, a desktop app in **Electron.js** and build upon the existing back end. The back end was written in **express.js** and **Node.js** using **AWS**.

Axxes IT consultancy / Java software consultant

AUG 2018 - JAN 2019, ANTWERP & BRUSSELS

My time at Axxes started with a 3 month traineeship, where we learned mostly about back end Java technologies, a bit of front end and types of project management.

At **Belga News Agency**, I worked as an Axxes consultant. I helped with developing a user management tool in **Java EE** for the back end and **Angular** for the front end. The Java app was collaborative and I was the sole developer for the Angular app.

Cloudranger / Traineeship

MAR 2018 - MAY 2018, LETTERKENNY - IRELAND

Before the acquisition of Cloudranger by Druva, I had a traineeship that was front end focussed. I got to write an in house tool in **Angular** and rewrite their app from Angular.js to Angular. Here I've got my first experience in **AWS**.

Education

Applied informatics / Professional bachelor

SEP 2015 - AUG 2018, GEEL - BELGIUM

The first 1.5 years I've got to learn about all different aspects of IT including Infrastructure, app development, business information technology, embedded devices and project management. After 1.5 years I've chosen to specialise in App Development.

Digital arts & entertainment

SEP 2014 - AUG 2015, KORTRIJK - BELGIUM

Applied informatics

SEP 2013 - AUG 2014, GEEL - BELGIUM

Bookkeeping - informatics

SEP 2011 - JUN 2013, TURNHOUT - BELGIUM